The most bizarre murder weapon ever used!
Duel is a action, thriller, tv movie film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Traveling businessman David Mann angers the driver of a rusty
tanker while crossing the California desert.
A simple trip turns deadly, as Mann struggles to stay on the road
while the tanker plays cat and mouse with his life.
David Mann, played by Dennis Weaver.
Mrs. Mann, played by Jacqueline Scott.
Cafe Owner, played by Eddie Firestone.
Bus Driver, played by Lou Frizzell.
Man in Cafe, played by Gene Dynarski.
Lady at Snakerama, played by Lucille Benson.
Duel is a 1971 American road action thriller film directed by
Steven Spielberg in his feature film debut.
It centers on a traveling salesman David Mann (Dennis Weaver) driving
his car through rural California to meet a client.
However, he finds himself chased and terrorized by the
mostly unseen driver of a semi-truck.
The screenplay by Richard Matheson adapts his own short story of the same name, published in the April 1971 issue of Playboy,
and based on an encounter on November 22, 1963, when a trucker dangerously cut him off on a California freeway.
Produced by Universal Television as a television film, Duel originally aired as a
part of the ABC Movie of the Week series on November 13, 1971.
It later received an international theatrical release by Universal Pictures in an
extended version featuring scenes shot after the film's original TV broadcast.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with
Spielberg's direction being singled out for praise.
It has since been recognized as an influential cult classic and
one of the greatest television films ever made.
The film explores themes of california, panic,
chase, gas station, falsely accused.
The tone is intense.